A Guide to the Collection of William Stanley Braithwaite, 1910-1930
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Collection of William Stanley Braithwaite, 1910-1930
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
6787
This collection consists of 366 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was deposited on 15 May 1962.
Scope and Content Information
Collection of letters, photographs, manuscripts, sonnets, poetry, broadside, postcards, telegrams, drawing, material relating to Braithwaite's anthologies of American poetry, also including "Ten Best Books of Poems," 1912-1926, and a questionnaire.
Contents List
- Correspondence re. Braithwaite Anthology Fund 1922 (Box 1)
  Letters by:
  - Katharine Adams (Box 1)
  - Mary Aldis (Box 1)
  - Mary W. Arlington (Box 1)
  - Morris G. Bishop (Box 1)
  - C. G. Blanden (Box 1)
  - John Black (Box 1)
  - Gamaliel Bradford (Box 1)
  - Edith Brower (Box 1)
  - Witter Bynner (Box 1)
  - Le Baron Cooke (Box 1)
  - Olive Tilford Dargan (Box 1)
  - Grace Atherton Dennen (Box 1)
  - Sophie H. Duckworth (Box 1)
  - Henry Van Dyke (Box 1)
  - (Miss) George Elliston (Box 1)
  - William W. Ellsworth (Box 1)
  - Anita Fitch (Box 1)
  - Agnes Lee Freer (Box 1)
  - Louise Ayres Garnett (Box 1)
  - Joy Gerhaulet (Box 1)
  - Amanda Benjamin Hall (Box 1)
  - H. L. Koopman (Box 1)
  - Elias Lieberman (Box 1)
  - Herbert H. Longfellow (Box 1)
  - Florence Van Fleet Lyman (Box 1)
  - J. R. McCarthy (Box 1)
  - Marjorie Meeker (Box 1)
  - G. H. Palmer (Box 1)
  - Bliss Perry (Box 1)
  - Lilla Cabot Perry (Box 1)
  - Frances Dickenson Pinder (Box 1)
  - Gertrude M. Richards (Box 1)
  - Lew Sarett (Box 1)
  - Jay G. Sigmund (Box 1)
  - Alex Sutherland (Box 1)
  - Ethel Arnold Tilden ("Alice Arnold) (Box 1)
  - Harold Vinal (Box 1)
  - John Hall Wheelock (Box 1)
  - Rufus R. Wilson (Box 1)
  - Henry W. Winslow (Box 1)
  - Ruth Comfort (Box 1)
  - Mitchell Young (Box 1)
- "Ten Best Books of Poems, 1912-1926": Questionnaire filled out by: (Box 1)
  - William Stanley Braithwaite (Box 1)
  - Henry S. Candy (Box 1)
  - Jessie B. Rittenhouse (Box 1)
  - George S. Seymour (Box 1)
  - Charles Wharton Stock (Box 1)
  - Louis Untermeyer (Box 1)
  - Clement Wood (Box 1)
- General Correspondence Re. Anthologies (Box 1)
  - Adams, Katharine (Box 1)
    - "A Sonnet" [n.d.], Typescript, signed. 1 p. (Box 1)
      "Because sometimes when fragile jewelled mist...].
    - "A Sonnet" [n.d.], Typescript, signed. 1 p. (Box 1)
      "I shall remember stones..."
    - "Whiteness" [n.d.], Typescript, signed. 1 p. (Box 1)
      [A poem]
    - Katharine Adams to Braithwaite 1920 October 24, ALS. 3 pp. (Box 1)
  - Aiken, Conrad "Saturday", ALS. 1 p. (Box 1)
    Conrad Aiken to Braithwaite
  - Aldis, Mrs. Arthur T. [n.d], Drawing (Box 1)
    Mrs. Aldis.
  - Allen, Hervey 1926 August 24, ALS. 2 pp. (Box 1)
    Hervey Allen to Braithwaite
  - Altrocchi, Julia Cooley (Mrs. Rudolph) 1923-24, ALS. 1 p. (Box 1)
    Julia Cooley Altrocchi to Braithwaite
  - Anderson, Maxwell (Box 1)
    - Maxwell Anderson to Braithwaite 1922 November 8, ALS. 1 p. (Box 1)
    - Maxwell Anderson [Portrait]. [n.d.], Photograph (Box 1)
    - Maxwell Anderson [snapshot] [n.d.], Photograph (Box 1)
  - Anderson, Sherwood [1921], Photograph. (Box 1)
    Sherwood Anderson
  - Aughiltree, Ruth __ February 22, TNS. 1 P. (Box 1)
    Ruth Aughiltree to Braithwaite
  - Auslander, Charles __ October 24, ALS. 2 pp. (Box 1)
    Charles Auslander to Braithwaite
  - Austin, Mary 1926 August 23, TNS. 1 p. (Box 1)
    Mary Austin to Braithwaite
  - Bacon, Leonard 1926 December 4, TLS. 1 P. (Box 1)
    Leonard Bacon to Braithwaite.
  - Bailey, Margaret Emerson [1930 February 18], ALS. 1 p. (Box 1)
    Margaret Emerson Bailey to Braithwaite.
  - Bartlett, Ruth Petite (Mrs. Walter S.) [1920 or 1926], April 9, ALS. 3 pp. (Box 1)
    Ruth Petite Bartlett to Braithwaite
  - Bates, Katharine Lee (Box 1)
    - "Angels" [poem] [ca. 1924 July 10], Typescript, signed. 2 pp. (Box 1)
    - Katharine Lee Bates to Braithwaite 1923 November 12, TLS. 2 pp. (Box 1)
    - Katharine Lee Bates to Braithwaite 1924 January 20, TLS. 2 PP. (Box 1)
  - Beer, Morris Abel 1926 July 23, ALS. 1 p. (Box 1)
    Morris Abel Beer to Braithwaite. [Enclosure: printed description Beer's course in poetry writing at C.C.N.Y., 1926]
  - Bellaman, Henry 1925 October 22, ALS. 2 pp. (Box 1)
    Henry Bellaman to Braithwaite
  - Benet, Stephen Vincent [n.d.], TNS. 1 p. (Box 1)
    Stephen Vincent Benet to Braithwaite
  - Benet, William Rose [n.d.], Typescript, sighed, & with autograph corrections. 8 pp. (Box 1)
    "Poetry In the Middle Atlantic States".
  - William Rose Benet, to Braithwaite 1926 August 17, ANS. 1 p. (Box 1)
  - William Rose Benet to Braithwaite [n.d.], ALS. 1 p. (Box 1)
  - Briggs Margaret Perkins (Box 1)
    - "Goldenrod" [n.d.], Typescript, signed. 1 p. (Box 1)
    - "Harvesters" [n.d.], Typescript. 1 p. (Box 1)
    - "Late August Days" [n.d.], Typescript. 1 p. (Box 1)
    - "Sonnet" [When I have Made My Own...] [n.d.], Typescript. 1 p. (Box 1)
    - "These Winds" [n.d.], Typescript (Box 1)
    - Margaret Perkins Briggs to Braithwaite 1925 October 3, ALS. 1 p. (Box 1)
    - Margaret Perkins Briggs to Braithwaite 1926 January 6, ALS. 1 p. (Box 1)
  - Buck, Howard 1925 September 30, ANS. 1 p. (Box 1)
    Howard Buck to Braithwaite
  - Burgess, Dorothy 1925 October 4, ANS. 1 p. (Box 1)
    Dorothy Burgess to Braithwaite
  - Burton, Richard (Box 1)
    - Richard Burton to Braithwaite __ February 15, ALS. 4 pp. (Box 1)
    - Richard Burton to Braithwaite __ March 4, ALS. 2 pp. (Box 1)
    - Richard Burton to Braithwaite __ April 12, ALS. 1 p. (Box 1)
    - Richard Burton to Braithwaite __ May 28, ALS. 1 p. (Box 1)
  - Bynner, Witter (Box 1)
    - Witter Bynner to Braithwaite 1926 May 20, TL initialed. 6 pp. (Box 1)
    - Witter Bynner to Miss __ Mirick 1930 April 8, TNS. 1 p. (Box 1)
  - Chapin, Katherine Garrison (Mrs. Francis Biddle) 1930 January 29, ALS. 2 pp. (Box 1)
    Katherine Garrison Chapin to Braithwaite
  - Cheyney, E. Ralph (Box 1)
    - E. Ralph Cheyney to Braithwaite 1926 August 6, TLS. 1 p. (Box 1)
    - E. Ralph Cheney to Braithwaite 1926 October 21, TLS. 1 p. (Box 1)
    - E. Ralph Cheyney to Braithwaite [after 1926 October] "Tuesday", TLS. 1 p. (Box 1)
    - Lucia Trent & E. Ralph Cheyney to Braithwaite 1930 January 24, ALS. 1 p. (Box 1)
    - E. Ralph Cheyney [n.d.], Photograph. signed. (Box 1)
  - Chesson, Nora (Box 1)
    - "A Deserted Woman" [n.d.], AMS [signed?]. 2 pp. (Box 1)
      [poem]
    - W. H. Chesson to Braithwaite 1910 October 21, ALS. 4 pp. [with envelope] (Box 1)
  - Coates, Archie Austin 1918 July 7, ANS. 1 p. (Box 1)
    Archie Austin Coates to Braithwaite
  - Coatsworth, Elizabeth J. 1923 October 11, ANS. 2 pp. (Box 1)
    Elizabeth J. Coatsworth to Braithwaite.
  - Coffin, Robert P. Tristram 1930 February 4, TNS. 1 p. (Box 1)
    Robert P. Tristram Coffin to Braithwaite
  - Conant, Isabel (Box 1)
    - "Bloom" [n.d.], Typescript signed. 1 p. (Box 1)
    - Isabel Conant to Braithwaite [n.d.], ALS. 2 pp. (Box 1)
  - Cone, Helen Gray 1930 January 25, ALS. 1 p. (Box 1)
    Helen Gray Cone to Braithwaite
  - Conkling, Grace Hugard (Mrs. Roscoe B. Conkling) (Box 1)
    - Grace Hugard Conkling to Braithwaite 1913 April 12, TLS. 1 p. (Box 1)
    - Grace Hugard Conkling to Braithwaite 1914 December 27, TLS. 1 p. (Box 1)
    - Grace Hugard Conkling to Braithwaite 1917 January 28, TLS. 1 p. (Box 1)
  - Cooksley, S. Bert __ September 2, TLS. 1 p. (Box 1)
    S. Bert Cooksley to Braithwaite
  - Copeland, Charles Townsend [n.d.], Reproduction of drawing. Charles Townsend Copeland. (Box 1)
  - Crawford, Nelson Antrim (Box 1)
    - "Converted" [n.d.], Typescript. 4 pp. (Box 1)
    - Nelson Antrim Crawford to Braithwaite 1926 September 13, TLS. 1 p. (Box 1)
  - Crew, Mrs. Henry (Box 1)
    - "Attis[one-act verse play] [n.d.], Typescript. 4 pp. (Box 1)
    - Mrs. Henry Crew to Braithwaite [1913 December 18], A. Postcard S. 1 p. (Box 1)
  - Cross, Wilbur L. 1914 October 26, TNS. 1 p. (Box 1)
    Wilbur L. Cross to Braithwaite
  - Damon, S. Foster 1923 October 12, ANS. 1 p. (Box 1)
    S. Foster Damon to Braithwaite
  - Dargan, Olive (Box 1)
    - Olive Dargen to Braithwaite 1922 December 11, ALS. 5 pp. (Box 1)
    - Olive Dargan to Braithwaite 1925 October 1, ALS. 4 pp. (Box 1)
    - Olive Dargan to Braithwaite [n.d.], ALS. 2 pp. (Box 1)
    - Olive Dargan 1922, Photograph (Box 1)
    - Olive Dargan 1922, Photograph (Box 1)
  - Davidson, Donald (Box 1)
    - Donald Davidson to Braithwaite 1923 October 5, TLS. 1 p. (Box 1)
    - Donald Davidson to Braithwaite 1923 October 18, TLS. 1 p. (Box 1)
  - Davies, Mary Carolyne [n.d.], Carbon Typescript. 1 p. [With ANS in pencil to Braithwaite] (Box 1)
    "The Autos Find Their Way to God" [poem].
  - Davis, Fannie S. 1912 March 24, ALS. 2 pp. (Box 1)
    Fannie S. Davis, to Braithwaite
  - Davis, John Johnson 1923 October 5, ALS. 1 p. (Box 1)
    John Johnson Davis to Braithwaite
  - Dodd, Lee Wilson 1930 March 22, ALS. 1 p. (Box 1)
    Lee Wilson Dodd to Miss _ Mirick
  - Dole, Nathan Haskell [n.d.], Typescript. 6 pp. (Box 1)
    "Milton and his Rimes." [article]
  - Dond, Margery 1930 April 16, ALS. 1 p. (Box 1)
    Margery Dond to Mrs. Smyth.
  - Douglas, Marjory Stoneman (Box 1)
    - Marjory Stoneman Douglas to Braithwaite 1923 October 5, ALS. 1 p. (Box 1)
    - Marjory Stoneman Douglas to Braithwaite 1923 October 29, ALS. 1 p. (Box 1)
  - Drisback, Glenn Ward (Box 1)
    - Glenn Ward Drisback to E---- M----. 1930 January 22, ALS. 1 p. (Box 1)
    - Glenn Ward Drisback to Braithwaite 1930 January 22, ANS. 1 p. (Box 1)
  - Edwardine, Sister M. 1928 December 10, ALS. 2 pp. (Box 1)
    Sister M. Edwardine to Braithwaite
  - Elliott, Ellen Coit 1923 October 12, ALS. 2 pp. (Box 1)
    Ellen Coit Elliott to Braithwaite
  - Ellsworth, William W. 1917 January 30, ALS. 2 pp. (Box 1)
    William W. Ellsworth to Braithwaite
  - Evans, Donald [n.d.], Photograph (Box 1)
    Donald Evans
  - Flexner, Hortense (Box 1)
    - "The Singer" [n.d.], Typescript. 1 p. (Box 1)
      [poem][on same sheet: An initialed, H.F.K. to Braithwaite]
    - Hortense Flexner [n.d.], Photograph (Box 1)
  - Fletcher, John Gould __ May 11, ALS. 1 P. (Box 1)
    John Gould Fletcher to Braithwaite
  - Freer, Agnes Lee (Box 1)
    - Agnes Lee Freer to Braithwaite 1912 March 22, TLS. 2 pp. (Box 1)
    - Agnes Lee Freer to Braithwaite 1917 February 5, TLS. 2 pp. (Box 1)
    - Agnes Lee Freer to Braithwaite 1930 March 31, ALS. 3 pp. (Box 1)
  - Frost Elizabeth Holliston (Box 1)
    - Elizabeth Holliston Frost to Mrs. __ Merrick 1930 February 8, ALS. 4 pp. (Box 1)
    - Elizabeth Holliston Frost to Braithwaite [1931 July ?], ALS. 4 pp. (Box 1)
  - Giltinan, Caroline (Box 1)
    - Caroline Giltinan to Braithwaite 1929 __, TLS. 3 pp. (Box 1)
    - Caroline Giltinan to Braithwaite 1929 August 28, ALS. 2 pp. (Box 1)
  - Ginsburg, Louis (Box 1)
    - "Midnight Rain" [poem] [n.d.], AMS signed. 1 p. (Box 1)
    - Louis Ginsburg to Miss __ Mirick 1930 March 14, ANS. 1 p. (Box 1)
  - Goldberg, Isaac 1916 September 30, TLS. 1 p. (Box 1)
    Issac Goldberg to __ O'Brien
  - Gorman, Herbert S. [n.d.], ALS. 2 pp. (Box 1)
    Herbert S. Gorman to Miss __ Jackson
  - Haight, Dorothy 1926 January 29, ALS. 1 p. (Box 1)
    Dorothy Haight to Braithwaite
  - Hansen, Harry 1926 August 2, TLS. 2 pp. (Box 2)
    Harry Hansen to Braithwaite
  - Harding, Ruth Guthrie [n.d.], AMS initialed. 1 p. (Box 2)
    "After Six Years..."
  - Harrison, Henry [n.d.], TLS. 1 p. (Box 2)
    Henry Harrison to Braithwaite
  - Helton, Roy [n.d.], Photograph (Box 2)
    Roy Helton
  - Hersey, Harold __ May 29, ALS. 2 pp. (Box 2)
    Harold Hersey to Braithwaite
  - Hickson, Kattaine Tynan 1912 August 16, ALS. 2 pp. (Box 2)
    Kattaine Tynan Hickson to Mrs. __ Gildinan.
  - Hill, Frank 1927 August 23, ALS. 2 pp. (Box 2)
    Frank Hill to Braithwaite
  - Hill, Hazel (Box 2)
    -Five photographs-
  - Hillyer, Robert (Box 2)
    - "The Coming Forth By Day..." [n.d.], AMS note signed (Box 2)
    - Robert Hillyer to Braithwaite [n.d.], ALS. 1 p. (Box 2)
    - Robert Hillyer [n.d.], Photograph. (Box 2)
  - Horgan, Paul 1928 August 24, ANS. 1 p. (Box 2)
    Paul Horgan to Braithwaite
  - Howells, William Dean 1912 August 21, ANS. 1 p. (Box 2)
    William Dean Howells to Braithwaite
  - Javitz, Alexander 1926 September 1, TNS. 1 p. (Box 2)
    Alexander Javitz to Braithwaite
  - Jeffers, Robinson [n.d.], Photograph (Box 2)
    Robinson Jeffers
  - Jenkens, Oliver 1928 January 5, ALS. 1 p. (Box 2)
    Oliver Jenkens to Braithwaite
  - Johnson, Josephine 1923 October 4, ANS. 1 p. (Box 2)
    Josephine Johnson to Braithwaite
  - Johnson, R.V. 1916 September 4, TLS. 1 p. (Box 2)
    Johnson to Braithwaite
  - Johnson, R. V. 1916 September 4, TLS. 1 p. (Box 2)
    R.V. Johnson to Braithwaite
  - Johnson, Willard 1926 August 8, TLS. 1 p. (Box 2)
    Willard Johnson to Braithwaite
  - Jones, Thomas S. (Box 2)
    - Thomas S. Jones to Braithwaite 1910 July 27, Postcard. 1 p. (Box 2)
    - "Urbs Beata" [sonnet]. [1912 Easter], broadside signed, with note, 1 p. (Box 2)
    - Thomas [S. Jones] to Braithwaite [Thursday], ALS. 5 pp. (Box 2)
    - "Mosher Books by Thomas S. Jones, Jr." [n.d.], broadside. 1 p. (Box 2)
    - Norreys Jephson O'Conor: After Reading 'Sonnets of the Cross'/to Thomas S. Jones, Jr." [February 1924], broadside. 1 p. (Box 2)
    - "Sonnets of the Cross" [n.d.], broadside, 4 pp. (Box 2)
      "Review"
    - Dr. Lynn Harold Hough: "The Lion In His Den" [n.d.], broadside, 4 pp. (Box 2)
      [Review of "Sonnets of the Cross"]
    - "If my work..." [n.d.], Typed Note. 1 p. (Box 2)
    - T[h]om[mas S. Jones] to Braithwaite 1926 July 24, TLS. 1 p. (Box 2)
  - Joyce, James, Photograph. [taken in Zurich] (Box 2)
    James Joyce
  - Kiper, Florence (Box 2)
    - The Jew to Jesus, and other poems. [n.d.], Typescript, signed. 55 pp. (Box 2)
    - Florence Kiper [& daughter?] [n.d.], Photograph. (Box 2)
    - "Florence Kiper/Reader and Lecturer" [n.d.], broadside. 4 pp. (Box 2)
  - Knapp, Lewis M. 1926 January 21, ALS. (Box 2)
    Lewis M. Knapp to Braithwaite
  - Lafollette, Suzanne [1930?] March 19, ALS. 2 pp. (Box 2)
    Suzanne Lafollette to Braithwaite
  - Laramore, Vivian P. 1930 April 8, ALS. 2 pp. (Box 2)
    Vivian P. Laramore to Braithwaite
  - Lawrence, D. H. [n.d.], Photograph. signed. (Box 2)
    D. H. Lawrence
  - Ledoux, Louis V. (Box 2)
    - Louis V. Ledoux to Braithwaite 1912 December 18-1920 October 26, 50 TLS. ca. 70 pp. (Box 2)
    - Louis V. Ledoux to Braithwaite 1913 December 27-1915 February 24, 22 ALS. ca. 30 pp. (Box 2)
  - Lee, Lawrence 1930 January 24, ALS. 1 p. (Box 2)
    Lawrence Lee to Braithwaite
  - Lee, Muna (Mrs. Luis Munoz-Marin) 1923 October 6, ALS. 2 pp. (Box 2)
    Muna Lee to Braithwaite
  - Lewis, Emily Sargent (Mrs. Wilfred) (Box 2)
    - "Diversions" [n.d.], Typescript signed. 1 p. (Box 2)
    - Emily Sargent Lewis to Braithwaite 1913 June 10, ALS. 1 p. (Box 2)
  - Lewis, May 1930 January 28, ALS. 1 p. (Box 2)
    May Lewis to Braithwaite
  - Litter, Katherine D. __ December 28, ALS. 2 pp. (Box 2)
    Katherine D. Litter to Braithwaite
  - Low, Benjamin R. C. [n.d.], Typescript signed. 1 p. (Box 2)
    "Requiescat" [poem]
  - Lowe, Robert Lidell (Box 2)
    - "No Harvest"[poem] [n.d.], Typescript signed. 1 p. (Box 2)
    - "O Wise Were They" [n.d.], Typescript signed. 1 p. (Box 2)
    - "Woman Ploughing" [n.d.], Typescript signed. 1 p. (Box 2)
    - Robert Lidell Lowe to Braithwaite 1929 August 26, TLS. 1 p. (Box 2)
  - Lowell, Miss [Amy] (Box 2)
    - Miss Lowell to Braithwaite __ June 21, Telegram. 1 p. (Box 2)
    - Miss Lowell to Braithwaite __ June, Telegram. 1 p. (Box 2)
  - MacManus, Seimas 1910 July 20, TNS. 1 p. (Box 2)
    Seimas MacManus to Braithwaite
  - Macy John 1913 April 1, ANS. 1 p. (Box 2)
    John Macy to Braithwaite
  - Masters, Edgar Lee [n.d.], Photograph. (Box 2)
    Edgar Lee Masters
  - Mearns, Hughes 1923 June 18, ALS. 1 p. (Box 2)
    Hughes Mearns to Braithwaite
  - Mencken, H. L. 1916 December 6, TLS. 1 p. (Box 2)
    H. L. Mencken to Braithwaite. [enclosure: petition, "A Protest" re. attacks on Dreiser]
  - Montgomery, Roselle Mercier 1926 June 16, ALS. 1 p. (Box 2)
    Roselle Mercier Montgomery to Braithwaite
  - Moore, Marianne [n.d.], ANS. 1 p. (Box 2)
    Marianne Moore to Braithwaite
  - Moore, Virginia 1926 August 16, TLS. 1 p. (Box 2)
    Virginia Moore to Braithwaite.
  - Morelov, J. R. (Box 2)
    - J. R. Morelov to Braithwaite [1925 July 23], AL. initialed. 5 pp. (Box 2)
      J. R. Morelov to Braithwaite
    - J. R. Morelov to Braithwaite [n.d.], ALS. 5 pp. (Box 2)
  - Morris, Lloyd R. 1919 February 21, ALS. 1 p. (Box 2)
    Lloyd R. Morris to Braithwaite
  - [Mosher?], T. B. 1910, ALS. 1 p. (Box 2)
    T. B. [Mosher?] to Braithwaite
  - Musser, Benjamin __ September 27, ALS. 1 p. (Box 2)
    Benjamin Musser to Braithwaite
  - Nicholl, Louise Townsend [n.d.], Typescript signed. 3 pp. (Box 2)
    "The Common Sick". [poem]
  - O'Shell, Shaemas 1921 November 9, ALS. (Box 2)
  - Overton, Grant M. (Box 2)
    - Grant M. Overton to Braithwaite 1919 January 14, TLS. 1 p. (Box 2)
    - Grant M. Overton to Braithwaite 1919 January 28, TLS. 1 p. (Box 2)
  - Page, Curtis 1915 May 7, ALS. 1 p. (Box 2)
    Curtis Page to Braithwaite
  - Palmer, E.S. 1915 January 4, ALS. 3 pp. (Box 2)
    E. S. Palmer to Braithwaite.
  - Peabody, Josephine Preston [n.d.], Photograph (Box 2)
    Josephine Preston Peabody
  - Percy, William Alexander [n.d.], Photograph. (Box 2)
    William Alexander Percy
  - Phelps, William Lyon 1928 February 1, TLS. 1 p. (Box 2)
    William Lyon Phelps to Braithwaite
  - Phillips, Charles (Box 2)
    - Charles Phillips to Braithwaite 1926 January 20, TLS. 1 p. (Box 2)
    - Charles Phillips to Braithwaite 1926 February 24, ALS. 1 p. (Box 2)
  - Piper, Edwin Ford, Photograph, signed. (Box 2)
    Edwin Ford Piper
  - Putnam, Nina Wilcox [1917 __], TLS. 1 p. (Box 2)
    Nina Wilcox Putnam to Braithwaite
  - Purnell, Idelia (Box 2)
    - Idelia Purnell to Braithwaite 1925 November 24, ALS. 1 p. (Box 2)
    - Idelia Purnell to Braithwaite 1926 October 1, ALS. 2 pp. (Box 2)
  - Reese, Lizette Wordworth 1926 October 1, ALS. 1 p. (Box 2)
    Lizette Wordworth Reese to Braithwaite
  - Ridge, Lola [n.d.], Photograph (Box 2)
    Lola Ridge
  - Rittenhouse, Jessie B. __ August 15, TLS. 1 p. (Box 2)
    Jessie B. Rittenhouse to Braithwaite
  - Roberts, Cecil (Box 2)
    - Cecil Roberts to Braithwaite 1920 February 18, TLS. 1 p. (Box 2)
    - Cecil Roberts to Braithwaite 1920 March 27, ALS. 1 p. (Box 2)
    - Cecil Roberts to Braithwaite 1920 June 22, ALS. 2 pp. (Box 2)
  - Roberts, Elizabeth Madox [n.d.], Drawing. (Box 2)
    Elizabeth Madox Roberts
  - Robinson, Mrs. Douglas 1927 June 3, TLS. 3 pp. (Box 2)
    Mrs. Douglas Robinson to Braithwaite
  - Root, E. Merrill (Box 2)
    - E. Merrill Root to Braithwaite 1926 August 9, TLS. 1 p. (Box 2)
    - E. Merrill Root to Braithwaite 1926 August 21, TLS. 1 p. (Box 2)
  - Ryan, Katheryne, White 1925 December 3, ALS. 1 p. (Box 2)
    Katheryne White Ryan to Braithwaite. [enclosure: clippings]
  - Sanborn, J. 19__, November 24, ALS. 2 pp. (Box 2)
    J. Sanborn to __ Kline.
  - Sarett, Lew [n.d.], Photograph. (Box 2)
    Lew Sarett
  - Shaw, Frances (Box 2)
    - Frances Shaw to Braithwaite 1930 February 5, ALS. 1 p. (Box 2)
    - Frances Shaw to __. 1930 June 24, ANS. 2 pp. (Box 2)
  - Smyth, Florida Watts [1930?] April 15., ALS. 1 p. (Box 2)
    Florida Watts Smyth to Miss __ Mirick
  - Starrett, Vincent [n.d.], Photograph. signed. (Box 2)
    Vincent Starrett
  - Teasdale, Sara [n.d.], Photograph signed. (Box 2)
    Sara Teasdale
  - Tietjens, Eunice 1921 June 2, ANS. 2 pp. (Box 2)
    Eunice Tietjens to Braithwaite.
  - Trent, Lucia (Box 2)
    - Lucia Trent to Braithwaite 1921 June 2, ALS. 1 p. (Box 2)
    - Lucia Trent to Braithwaite 1930 February 12, ALS. 1 p. (Box 2)
  - Untermeyer, Louis (Box 2)
    - Louis Untermeyer to Braithwaite 1923 April 28, TLS. 1 p. (Box 2)
    - Louis Untermeyer to Braithwaite [1912?], A. Cards. 1 p. (Box 2)
    - Louis Untermeyer [n.d.], Photograph (Box 2)
  - Van Doren, Mark 1926 March 1, TLS. 1 p. (Box 2)
    Mark Van Doren to Braithwaite
  - Villon, George 1926 November 4, ALS. 2 pp. (Box 2)
    George Villon to Braithwaite
  - Vinal, Harold [n.d.], ALS. 2 pp. (Box 2)
  - Wheelock, John Hall (Box 2)
    - John Hall Whellock to Braithwaite [n.d.], TNS. 1 p. (Box 2)
    - John Hall Wheelock [n.d.], Photograph (Box 2)
  - Ward, May Williams 1925 December 19, ALS. 1 p. (Box 2)
    May Williams Ward to Braithwaite
  - Wood, Clement 1924 February 28, TNS. 1 p. (Box 2)
    Clement Wood to Braithwaite
  - Woodberry, __ E. [n.d.], ANS. 1 p. (Box 2)
    __ E. Woodberry to Braithwaite
  - Wooley, Mary E. 1926 October 19, TLS. 1 p. (Box 2)
    Mary E. Wooley to Braithwaite
  - Wright, Willard Huntington. (Box 2)
    [S. S. Van Dine]
    - Manuscripts (Box 2)
      - "Doris" [poem] [n.d.], Typescript. 1 p. (Box 2)
      - "The Nativity" [poem] [n.d.], Typescript. 1 p. (Box 2)
      - "A Sensualist to Christ" [poem] [n.d.], Typescript. 1 p. (Box 2)
      - "The Violin" [poem] [n.d.], Typescript. 2 pp. (Box 2)
    - Letters (Box 2)
      - Willard Huntington Wright to Braithwaite 1908 March 4, TLS. 2 pp. (Box 2)
      - Willard Huntington Wright to Braithwaite 1908 March 17, ALS. 3 pp. (Box 2)
      - Willard Huntington Wright to Braithwaite 1909 February 20, TLS. 2 pp. (Box 2)
      - Willard Huntington Wright to Braithwaite 1910 January 12, TLS. 1 p. (Box 2)
      - Willard Huntington Wright to Braithwaite 1911 December 12, TLS. 1 p. (Box 2)
      - Willard Huntington Wright to Braithwaite 1928 July 6, TLS. 2 pp. (Box 2)
      - Willard Huntington Wright to Braithwaite 1928 July 14, TLS. 1 p. (Box 2)
      - Willard Huntington Wright to Braithwaite 1928 September 26, TLS. 1 p. (Box 2)
      - Willard Huntington Wright to Braithwaite 1929 January 2, TLS. 1 p. (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 2)
      - Willard Huntington Wright [n.d.], Photograph (Box 2)
  - Unidentified Authorship (Box 2)
    - [Braithwaite:] "On A March Evening" [n.d.], Typescript (Box 2)
      [Essay on Williard Huntington Wright].
    - Chard __ to Braithwaite 1925 July 26, ALS. 2 pp. (Box 2)